## **James Curlee**

Senior Software Engineer, Staff Software Engineer, Full Stack Software Engineer

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior level software engineer with 20+ years of software development across a multitude of industry leading technology companies. Have zeal for solving complex problems and enthusiasm for learning new software skills and tools. My vast professional experience has given me an acuminate ability to efficiently context switch between coding, pull requests, meetings, documentation, debugging and collaborating with peers. I value ensuring high software quality up front by following proven methodologies. I enjoy working for companies that promote and support innovation and managing tech debt and have highly collaborative development teams.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages	Ruby, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, Perl, C++
Frameworks / Libraries	Ruby on Rails, React.js, Express, Node.js, Vue.js, Vite, Django
Databases, Formats	PostgreSQL, MySQL, GraphQL, JSON, XML
Cloud, CI/CD workflows	Heroku, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Vite, Jenkins, CircleCi, GitHub Actions
Testing tools / utilities	Rspec, FactoryBot, Jest, Vitest, Mocha, Chai, Factorybot, Postman
Package Managers	NPM, Bundler,
Shells, OS, Agile tools	Bash, Zsh, Unix, Linux, MacOS, Git, GitHub, Jira

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Studio Source Yearbooks, Colgate, WI

August 2022 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Engineering responsibilities included prioritizing new features and deliverables, roadmap planning, collecting requirements, reporting status to stakeholders, developer feedback, performance reviews, mentoring and composing plans to address technical debt within the existing codebase.
- Front end stack involved Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3 (used in their Dashboard and Storefronts apps)
- Back end stack involved PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Python, RabbitMQ, AWS (S3, EC2).
- Developed 70+ unit tests using FactoryBot, Faker, RSpec for all of our API models.
- Integrated and used Rubocop (Rails linter) and ESlint (Javascript linter) to improve code quality.
- Used Retool app to develop SQL based internal reports for stakeholders across the company.
- Used Heroku for application deployment, monitoring and managing config variables.
- Worked with COO to begin using agile methodologies and implemented a 2 week Sprint cycle (capacity planning, backlog grooming, writing stories to address tech debt, story pointing)
- Responsible for onboarding and mentoring new developers

Senior Software Engineer

- Full Stack developer responsibilities included implementing new features, resolving critical bugs, peer code reviews, mentoring and onboarding mid level developers, collaborating with QA to test features and bug fixes, coordinating with Cloud Engineering on CI/CD and Docker & Kubernetes setup.
- Front end development was in React.js (micro architecture approach) and Jest for testing.
- Backend stack included Express (Node.js), Typescript, PostgreSQL, Mocha, Chai, GraphQL
- Agile 2 week Sprint cycle (capacity planning, dev work, demo, QA collaboration, story pointing, retro)
- Development tasks involved using AWS (S3, EC2), Docker, Kubernetes (K8s) for container management
- Collaborated with Engineers, Product Managers, Designers, QAs, DevOps and Product Analysts

## American Financing, Aurora, CO

October 2017 - December 2018

Senior Software Engineer

- Full stack developer for the consumer experience team. Responsibilities included implementing new features, resolving critical bugs, collaborating with Cloud Engineering for testing automations and coordinating bi-weekly code deployments, working with QA to test code across multiple browsers.
- Followed Agile practices (Jira, Bitbucket, pointing stories, two week Sprint cycle).
- Front end stack was HTML5, CSS3, Stimulus JavaScript. Backend stack was Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, RSpec for unit and integration testing. Used GitHub, Postman, Keybase.

#### Pinnacol Assurance, Denver, CO

January 2016 - October 2017

Software Developer II

- Full stack developer. Technologies used were Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JSON API, Foundation, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, Docker, Minitest, RSpec, Node.js, Github, and Postman.
- The Business support and development teams followed Agile practices (Jira, Kanban, Scrum).
- Responsibilities included working with business analysts to prioritize user stories and review customer requirements, collaborating with QA teams to coordinate testing code changes, deploying software builds and performing peer code reviews using GitHub.
- Our team followed Test Driven Development and used Jenkins for CI/CD.

#### Intel, Fort Collins, CO

November 2005 - August 2015

Senior Software Engineer

- Tech lead for the ERC (Electrical Rule Checks) software team for 5 years. Responsibilities included
  delivering major software enhancements and critical bug fixes, code deployment, tracking and
  prioritizing customer requests, interfacing with a broad team of design engineers across multiple sites
  and time zones and training and mentoring interns and mid level engineers.
- Developed critical features for a CPU verification and validation tool tracking Dashboard web app (Ruby on Rails backend, MySQL, Javascript front end) used in our production environment thru tape in.
- Full tech stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, CGI, PHP, RSpec, REST, MySQL.

Raytheon, Aurora, CO

February 2004 - October 2005

Software Engineer II

General Electric, Melbourne, FL

January 2000 - October 2003

Software Engineer

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in both Computer & Electrical Engineering · University of Florida (1996 - 1999)

Curlee 2 of 2